Guide to the Breast Cancer and Environmental Risk Factors Program records, 1995-2010
Breast Cancer and Environmental Risk Factors Program records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Breast Cancer and Environmental Risk Factors Program records, 1995-2010
24-19-3783
Cornell University.Breast Cancer and Environmental Risk Factors Program.
5 cubic feet.
Printed Materials, Publications, Reports, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes educational publications, grant reports, reprints of research publications, video tapes and CDs on teleconferences and workshops, and materials pertaining to the founding and history of the program.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Program on Breast Cancer and Environmental Risk Factors (BCERF) at Cornell University is devoted to lowering the risk and incidence of cancer by promoting methods of sound decision-making at personal and public levels.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes educational publications, grant reports, reprints of research publications, video tapes and CDs on teleconferences and workshops, and materials pertaining to the founding and history of the program.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.
Subjects:
Breast--Cancer; Environmental health.; Cancer--Environmental aspects.
Form and Genre Terms:
Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Additional material and digital versions can be found online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/14300
An archived version of the BCERF website can be found at the Internet Archive. http://wayback.archive-it.org/1716/*/http:/envirocancer.cornell.edu/
SERIES LIST
Series I. History
Series II. Reports, and Correspondence
Series III. Publications
Series IV. Meetings, Committees, and Conferences
Series V. Forums, Talks and Workshops
Series VI. Multimedia Resources
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. History
  - BCERF Founding Activities and History, August 1995-December 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - BCERF Founding White Paper, January-May 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, Including Founding and Early Planning Documents, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - BCERF Involvement in New York State Health Science Reseach Board, February-March 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - BCERF Visit from Senator Alfonse D'Amato, October 31, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - BCERF Web Launch and Media Coverage, Fall 1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - History, Sprecher Institute for Comparative Cancer Research, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - BCERF New York State Innovation in Breast Cancer Early Detection and Research Award, August 2006-March 2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - BCERF News Clippings and History, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - BCERF Articles in Newsletter of the Ithaca Breast Center Alliance, 1996-2003 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - BCERF Articles in CALS News, CALS Publications, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - BCERF Articles in the Alamo Breast Cancer Foundation Quarterly Update, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - BCERF Articles in the Cornell University Turfgrass Times (CUTT), 2002-2007 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - BCERF Articles in Trade Journals, 2000-2006 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series II. Reports, and Correspondence
  - BCERF e-Update Emails (Listserv), 2003-2009 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Building Awareness of BCERF Campaign, February 2007 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - BCERF Center for the Environment Reports and Newsletters, 1996-2004 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - BCERF Website Evaluation, 2000-2007 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - BCERF USDA-CSREES - Annual Report, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - BCERF Reports - Various Annual and Semi-Annual Reports, November 1995-November 1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - BCERF New York State Dept. of Health Quarterly Reports, July 1997-March 2004 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - BCERF New York State Dept. of Health Quarterly Reports, April 2004-December 2009 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - BCERF Final Technical Reports to the New York State Department of Health, 2002-2010 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Friends of the Sprecher Institute" Letter, March 20, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Dear Colleague" Letter Sponsored by New York State Senators and Congress Members, July 2006 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Congresswoman Nita Lowey Correspondence in Support of a Grant for BCERF, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - BCERF Correspondence with Senator Alfonse D'Amato and other correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Series III. Publications
  - BCERF Brochures (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - BCERF Newsletter, The Ribbon - Volumes 1-6, Spring 1996-Fall 2001 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - BCERF Newsletter, The Ribbon - Volumes 7-11, Winter 2002-Fall 2006 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - BCERF Newsletter, The Ribbon - Volumes 12-14, Winter 2007-Autumn 2009 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - BCERF Newsletter, The Ribbon - Evaluation Survey, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - BCERF Newsletter, The Ribbon - Evaluation Study, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - BCERF Newsletter, The Ribbon - Readership Maps, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - BCERF Newsletter, The Ribbon - Volume 12, Number 3 Article Translation - Spanish, Summer 2007 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - BCERF Publications - Critical Evalutations #1-7, May 1998-March 1999 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - BCERF Publications - Critical Evaluations #8-13, April 1999-June 2000 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - BCERF Publications - Brief: PBDEs, February 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - BCERF Publications - Brief: Soy Phytoestrogens, October 2009 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pesticide Applied Learning Series (PALS) - "Does Atrazine Affect the Risk of Cancer?", July 2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - BCERF Publications - Tip Sheets, June 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - BCERF Publications - Fact Sheets #1-25, November 1996-March 2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - BCERF Publications - Fact Sheets #26-57, March 1999-August 2007 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - BCERF Publications - Reprints from Peer-Reviewed Journals, 2000-2006 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - BCERF Tool Kit Module #6 - Talking About Pesticides in the Home and Neighborhood (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - BCERF EnviroChem and Cancer Database Spreadsheet, May 2004 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chemicals in the Workplace Potential for Exposure to Mammary Carcinogens, January 2010 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - BCERF - Brief and Other Materials: Turf Pesticides, 2006-2009 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - BCERF - Brief and Other Materials: Teachers and Breast Cancer Risk, 2006-2009 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pesticide Priority List, March-April 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Setting Priorities for Reviewing Carcinogens of Pesticides, 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Chemicals in the Workplace Database CD, February 2010 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - BCERF Women Firefighters Alert and Other Materials, December 2009 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - BCERF Estrogen Connection Project, Fall 2008 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - BCERF Pointers for Pets and People FAQs (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Turf Pesticides and Cancer Risk Database Instructional CD, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - BCERF Breast Cancer Incidence and Mortality Maps on the Web, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series IV. Meetings, Committees, and Conferences
  - BCERF Breast Cancer Discussion Groups (Predecessor to Ad Hoc), December 15, 1995, February 8, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, June 21, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, September 25, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, February 21, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, June 25, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, September 30, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, February 27, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - ICET Symposium - "The Science that Drives Policy: Pesticides, Diet, and Breast Cancer Risk", September 29-30, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - ICET Symposium with BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meetings, September 29-30, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, July 9, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, September 17, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, February 5, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, October 13, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, March 17, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, June 21, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, September 28, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, February 14, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, June 29, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, October 5, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, June 28, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, October 18, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - BCERF Ad Hoc Discussion Group Meeting, June 18, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - BCERF Educational Advisory Committee, 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - BCERF Satellite Videoconferences, February 1997, October 1997, April 2002 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - BCERF Executive Committee, October 1999-May 2001 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Core Group Meetings, April 1996 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Series V. Forums, Talks and Workshops
  - BCERF EnviroCancer Connections - Long Distance Learning, February 14, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - BCERF EnviroCancer Connections - Long Distance Learning, February 10, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - BCERF Long Distance Learning - Biomonitoring II, February 3, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, October 24, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, June 4, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, October 29, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, June 10, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, September 30, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, June 2, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, September 28, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, May 11, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, September 27, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, May 29, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, November 3, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - BCERF Regional Cancer and Environment Forum, September 22, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - College of Human Ecology Luncheon, May 7, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - BCERF Inservice Training, June 3-5, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Fire Service Women of New York State Workshop, Mountour Falls, September 20, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - BCERF Events Sponsored by Smith Barney, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Series VI. Multimedia Resources
  - Senator Alfonse D'Amato's Visit to BCERF - Slides, October 31, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Talking About Pesticides at Home and in the Neighborhood (BCERF-6) - Slides (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - BCERF/Rod D. on News Center 7, V-5415 (Box 2)
  - Breast Cancer Environmental Risk Factors - NC-7 Health Report, October 1996; V-5416 (Box 2)
  - Tools for Understanding Breast Cancer Risk - Videoconference, February 6, 1997; V-5417 (Box 2)
  - Tools for Understanding Breast Cancer Risk - Videoconference, February 6, 1997; V-5418 (Box 2)
  - Our Daughters, Our Selves - Videoconference Part 1, October 22, 1997; V-5419 (Box 2)
  - Our Daughters, Our Selves - Videoconference Part 2, October 22, 1997; V-5420 (Box 2)
  - BCERF: Sandra Steingraber Interview, February 12, 2002; V-5421 (Box 2)
  - Cleaning Products..... In Our Homes, In Our Environment - Part 1 of 2, V-5422 (Box 2)
  - Cleaning Products..... In Our Homes, In Our Environment - Part 2 of 2, V-5423 (Box 2)
  - Reducing Pesticide Exposure, with Charlotte Coffman, V-5424 (Box 2)
  - Spreadsheets on Chemicals in the Workplace: Potential for Exposure to Mammary Carcinogens, January 28, 2010; CD-706 (Box 2)
  - Endocrine Disruption - Envirocancer Connections Long Distance Learning, February 10, 2006; CD-707 (Box 2)
  - Breast Cancer and the Estrogen Connection - Environmental Estrogens in Everyday Products, 2009; CD-708 (Box 2)
  - Breast Cancer and the Estrogen Connection - Environmental Estrogens in Everyday Products - Handouts CD, 2009; CD-709 (Box 2)
  - Instructional CD for the Turf Pesticides and Cancer Risk Database, 2007; CD-710 (Box 2)
  - 52 Slides For Use with BCERF Tool Kit Module, "Talking about Pesticides in the Home and in the Neighborhood", CD-711 (Box 2)
  - Biomonitoring II - EnviroCancer Connections Long Distance Learning, February 3, 2006; CD-712 (Box 2)
  - Hillary Clinton Visits BCERF and Vet College (photos by Heather Clark), March 3, 2006; CD-713 (Box 2)
  - Posters (Box 3)
  - Posters (Box 4)
  - Copy of State of New York Resolution Establishing Breast Cancer and Women's Health Awareness Day, March 8, 2000 (Box 5)
  - BCERF Website - Print (Binder) (Box 5)
  - Pesticide Applied Learning Series (PALS) - Pieces of the Puzzle: Does Atrazine Affect the Risk of Cancer? (Binder; contains CD-703 and slides), July 2003 (Box 5)
  - EnviroCancer Connections: Resources for Health Profesionals (Binder; contains CD-704), 2004 (Box 5)
  - EnviroCancer Connections: Resources for Health Profesionals (Binder; contains CD-705), 2005 (Box 5)
  - Environment and Breast Cancer Teaching Tools for Change Kit - Core Lessons and Visual Aids (Box 5)
  - Environment and Breast Cancer Teaching Tools for Change - BCERF-1 Complete Tool Kit (Contains slides) (Box 5)
  - Long Distance Learning on Biomonitoring Topics: EnviroCancer Connections Project - Poster (Box 5)
  - Evaluating a Cancer Risk Reduction Program Over Time: An Outcome Indicator Approach - Poster (Box 5)
  - BCERF Health and Preventions Posters (Box 5)